练习 12-1：紧元音。不要关注拼写或意思，只要
Exercise 12-1, tense vowels. Don't pay attention to spelling or meaning. Just
记住：AH 栏里的词都带有同样的 AH 音。跟读。
remember that if you're in the AH column, they all have the same AH sound. Repeat.
One, at, out, ought, eyed, ate, eat, ooze, own. Two, bat, about, bought, bite, bait,
beat, boot, boat. 3. Cat, couch, cot, kite, cane, keys, cool, coat, 4. Chat,
chowder, chalk, child, chair, cheer, choose, chose, 5. Dad, doubt, dot, dial,
date, deed, do, don't. six fat found fought fight fate feet food phone seven
fallow fountain fall file fail feel fool full eight gas gown got kite gate gear
ghoul go nine hat how height, hate, heat, hoot, hope, tin, howl, howl, haul, hile,
hail, heel, whole, hole, eleven, jack, jowl, jock, giant, jail, jeep, jewel,
joal, twelve, crab, crowd, crawl, Crime, Crate, Creep, Cruel, Crow, Thirteen, Last,
Loud, Lost, Line, Late, Lee, Lou, Low, Fourteen, Mat, Mountain, Mop, Might, Mate,
Mean, Moon, Mown, Fifteen, Nat, Now, Not, Nate neat noon note 16 pal pound Paul pile
pale peel pool pole 17 rat round rot right rate real rule roll 18 sat sound soft
sight sail
19 shall shower shawl shine shade she shoe show 20 slap slouch slop slide slayed
sleep slew slow 21. Stag, stout, stop, style, stale, steal, stool, stole. 22.
Strap, stroud, straw, stride, straight, stream, strew, stroll. 23. Tap, town, top,
type, tape, team, tool, told. 24. That, Thou, Thar, Thine, They, These, Though.
25. Thang, Thousand, Thought, Thy, Thane, Thief, Throw. 26. Van, Vow, Volume, Viper,
Vein, Veal, Voodoo, Vote. 27. Wax. Wow. Wash. Wipe. Wane. Wheel. Woo. Woe. 28.
Yank. Yow. Yawn. Yikes. Yale. Year. You. Yo. 29. Zap. Zowie. Zombie. Xylophone.
Zany. Zebra. Zoo. Zo.